## **Onder Tapar**

LONDON, N17 MOBILE: (0) 7984 485 874

### ondertapar@gmail.com

## github.com/otapar

## **PROFILE**

Deadline-oriented Software Test Analyst with 6 years of experience in a manual testing environment and 2 years of experience in automation. Easily collaborate with developers and project managers to accomplish milestones. Solid history of discovering errors, resolving defects and ensuring client expectations are met with high quality software solutions. Experience working and hitting strict deadlines in highly pressured mission critical banking environment. Able to work on multiple projects at the same time. Extensive software testing lifecycle knowledge. Holds the most coveted advanced level tester certificate. Eager and able to learn new skills quickly with significant attention to detail and strong problem solving skills.

## SKILL S

- SQL, Oracle SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- soapUl, Postman
- Mocking applications
- lira
- HP Unified Functional Testing (UFT) (OTP)
- Selenium
- Python, VBScript

- Functional, integration & system, end to end testing, UAT, API testing
- Defect tracking tool
- Manual Testing
- Regression Testing
- Smoke Testing
- Waterfall, Agile, Scrum
- Excellent eye for detail

# **EDUCATION & OUALIFICATIONS**

ISTQB Advanced Level - Test Analyst Certified Tester

Nov 2017

Certificate No: 1117 CTAL 091

ISTOB Certified Tester Foundation Level

Oct 2012

Certificate No: 1012 CTFL 886

Bachelor of Economics

2002 - Mar 2007 Istanbul University Sep

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### QNB (Qatar National Bank) FinansBANK - IBTech

One of the top tier information technology companies and a subsidiary of QNB Finansbank A.S.

- Received and interpreted product owner specifications.
- Created and executed test cases for new product development based on the requirements.
- Created use cases, troubleshooted test issues, recorded test results, tracked and prioritized defects.
- Implemented testing plans and tested cases and presented testing results.
- > Analyzed the business requirement, created test strategy, generated the test plan and test case.
- Developed and executed the automation scripts with HP UFT.
- Tested services with mocking applications.
- Prepared data and tested web services with soapUI.
- Created SQL gueries to retrieve various data stored in database.
- Created test data in XML format.
- Root cause analysis on production bugs; created scenarios on test environment and verified fixes.
- Provided QA feedback for review retrospectives.
- Communicated with team members to coordinate completion.
- > Contributed to the preparation of the defect management, communication and Test scope sections of the test plan.
- Involved in Test data identification and gathering.
- Documented test cases and performed peer reviews on the team mate's work.
- > Reported over all sprint status and daily status.
- The projects i worked on were generally about the core banking products, such as; Direct Debiting System, Bill Collections, Wire Transfer (domestic and international (Western Union)), Supplier Chain Finance, Tax Payments. These projects were sometimes about adding new features to existing products, but mostly about the integrations with third parties (such as utility providers or other companies).

## Some of the Main Projects

## Reference Based Direct Debiting System (07/2018 - 01/2019)

This project was about adding a new feature to the existing direct debiting system. Initially a dealer can only get one reference number (and one limit) for the parent company. With this project one dealer is being able to get more than one reference for the same parent company. I conducted regression testing and experience based test techiques specially for the existing features of the product. I used **soapUI** and manually created files to create different type of data.

I developed automated test scripts using **HP UFT** for DDS dealer creation process.

### Platform Direct Debiting System (01/2018 - 07/2018)

On this project a very important new feature added to the existing DDS product for the e-commerce traders. While there had been two main roles -buyers and sellers- on standard DDS relation, with this project, one more role, Main Company, added to the product. Thereby e-commerce companies working in customer to customer basis, are being able to use DDS service. I performed all the manual testing on this project and also automated online invoice confirm process on Bank's web page by **Selenium**.

### ISKI Utility Bills Online Integrations (05/2017 - 08/2017)

ISKI is the unique water services provider in Istanbul. This project was about migrating bill collections from offline system to online. ISKI's online bill collection system was consisting different features like; debt inquiry, payment, cancelling payment, giving standing order and cancelling standing order, bulk debt inquiry (for standing orders). We integrated all these features with the

bank's core system. In terms of the number of the members of ISKI, it was a very important and risky project.

I used **soapUI** to call third party's services and **mocking applications** for the specific answers I wanted to simulate frequently. Also database queries both in production and in test environments to compare or create some kinds of data.

## POAS - Direct Debiting System (DDS) (10/2016 - 04/2017)

POAS is a petroleum company having the most extensive retail sales network offering service throughout Turkey. On this project credit card system integrated to the direct debiting system for the dealers of POAS.

I used POS machines in this project. **Postman** and **soapUI** for service testing and to create data.

## MDYS (07/2016 - 10/2016)

MDYS (central document management system) was the new implemented inhouse product for the documents stored during the transactions. I was responsible for the integration tests of this product with cash management products.

Agile methodology was used in this project. I conducted mainly user stories as test technique.

## • HSBC Bill Collection Payment Integrations (01/2016 - 07/2016)

On this project standing order utility bill collections of HSBC Turkey has been started to carry out over the core banking system of QNB Finansbank. I used **FileZilla** for file transfers. I conducted equivalence partitioning and error guessing test techniques while creating the test cases.

## • MFT (Managed File Transfer) (01/2015 - 01/2016)

The purpose of this project was to implement a new inhouse product that manages the secure transfer of data from source to another destination through a network which is named as MFT (Managed File Transfer). File exchange between trading partners and different layers of bank. Scrum methodology was used in this project.

I used **FileZilla** as an ftp client for file transfers and created different type of files by manually or by executing batches and **sql** gueries to see the results.

## Adding oft-used customers to the EFT screen (10/2013 - 01/2014)

The EFT (Electronic Fund Transfer) System provides real time transfer and real time gross settlement of Turkish Lira interbank payments. The purpose of this project was adding often used customer information dropdown box to the related page of banking application.

I used **sql** inquiries to create bulk data. Also I used **mocking applications** to mock the answers of third parties.

Mar

#### **ALTINBAS HOLDING A.S.**

A leading holding which has subsidiaries from jewelry, finance, energy and logistics sectors.

## *Auditor* 2008 - Jul 2013

- > Audited sales documents and related accounting records to verify the accuracy of sales tax returns and determined tax liabilities.
- > Examined wide range of documentation.

- Conducted audits to ensure legal compliance, to establish tax liability or to clarify reports.
- Prepared various reports which are required by the Turkish Tax Law.
- Prepared the contracts for these reports.
- > Followed up legislation and prepared and published circular about Tax Law.

#### SINES IMAGE IMPROVEMENTS

An agency which works for mainly promotions of computer brands.

**Promoter, Data Entry Clerk** (Part-time) **May 2006 - Mar 2007** 

- Worked in various malls and exhibitions to promote Hp and Dell branded products.
- Worked as a Data Entry Clerk for a campaign of Hp.

#### **TEKFENBANK A.S.**

A bank in Turkey which now operates under the name of Burgan Bank A.S.

Intern (Part-time)
Aug 2004

Jul 2004 -

> Served as an intern in operation and marketing departments of Tekfenbank A.S., Bayrampasa Branch.

## CERTIFICATES & SEMINARS

 Selenium WebDriver With Python 2019 www.udemy.com

- Intro to Computer Science 2017
  - www.udacity.com
- Custom Oracle SQL 2014
   Bilginç IT Academy